chrono24.co.uk 2016-04-10

# Chrono24 - Datenschutz

## Data Privacy Policy

As of: September 2015

Please note that this is a translation of our German Data Privacy Policy only. Our Data Privacy Policy only applies as defined in the [German version](http://www.chrono24.de/info/datenschutz.htm).  

We, Chrono24 GmbH, Haid-und-Neu-Str. 18, 76131 Karlsruhe, Germany (hereinafter referred to as **"Chrono24"** ), operate the online marketplace for high-quality watches (hereinafter referred to as **"Platform"** ) on www.chrono24.com. We are therefore responsible for the collection, processing and use of your personal data within the meaning of the German Data Privacy Act (BDSG) and the German Telemedia Act (TMG). The correct handling of your personal data is particularly important to us. We are therefore pleased to provide you with information on how your personal data is handled. 

We offer you the possibility to use a mobile device to access our platform or to use our services, either via a mobile application (app) or via a website optimized for mobile devices. The provisions of this Data Privacy Policy shall also apply to mobile access and the use of mobile devices. Reference is made to this Data Privacy Policy in all mobile applications and on all websites optimized for mobile devices.

We use your personal data in compliance with the applicable data privacy provisions. Below we will describe what data we collect, how we use it and what rights you have in terms of our use of your data:

**1.** **Scope and purpose of the collection, processing and use of personal data**

**a.** **When visiting our website**

When you visit our website, our servers temporarily save every access in a log file. The following data are automatically recorded without any action on your part and stored until such time as the profile is deleted:

  * the IP address of the accessing computer,
  * the date and time of access,
  * the name and URL of the accessed file,
  * the website from which you accessed our website (referrer),
  * the session ID,
  * the user agent.

These data are collected and processed for the purposes of facilitating use of our website (creating the connection), guaranteeing long-term system security and stability and optimizing our web service, as well as for internal statistical purposes. The IP address will be evaluated only in the event of attacks on our network infrastructure, for statistical purposes and to assert or defend against legal claims. After this your personal data will be deleted. 

In addition, we also set cookies and use web analysis and marketing services during visits to our website. You can find more detailed information on this in Sections 7 and 9.

**b.** **When registering as a user on the Platform**

Buyers, Private Sellers and dealers can all create a user account on our Platform. The following data must be provided to be able to set up a user account. We collect and process this data:

  * so that we know who our contractual partner is,
  * so that we can establish, shape the content of, process and alter contractual relationships with you regarding the use of our Platform and the services offered on it,
  * so that we can check the entered data for plausibility and,
  * so that we can contact you, where necessary, if we have any questions.

**aa.** **myChrono24 user account**

To register as a user and set up a user account the following data are mandatory:

  * your e-mail address,
  * your choice of password.

These data are needed to log into the user account.

In addition, you can provide additional user details voluntarily:

  * first name, last name,
  * address (street, zip code, city, country),
  * telephone.

These data are collected voluntarily to make it easier to contact you.

**bb.** **Private Sellers**

If you wish to publish offers on the Platform as a Private Seller, you first need a user account. To be able to publish an offer on the Platform, the following data must be provided: 

  * first name, last name,
  * address (street, zip code, city, country),
  * telephone.

**cc.** **Dealers**

To register as a dealer, the following data must be provided:

  * company,
  * contact (first name, last name),
  * address (street, zip code, city, country),
  * telephone,
  * e-mail address,
  * your choice of username,
  * your choice of password.

In addition, you can provide additional user details voluntarily:

  * fax,
  * cell phone number,
  * internet address.

These data are collected to make it easier to contact you.

**c.** **When using the Platform as a registered user/dealer**

When you use the Platform as a registered user/dealer, we collect the following data for statistical purposes, for market research, to make the Platform function smoothly, to shape our service in accordance with needs, and to personalize our services and advertisements: 

  * the length of your membership,
  * the type, frequency and intensity of your use of the website,
  * the history of viewed offers, manufacturer’s brands, and sellers.

**If you do not wish to take part in our programs for personalizing our services and advertising, you can[withdraw](https://www.chrono24.co.uk/user/delete-account.htm) your consent to participation at any time through your user account. **

**d.** **Use of the Trusted Checkout service**

You will need a user account in order to be able to initiate and conclude purchase agreements with dealers via our Trusted Checkout service. You must also provide the following information:

  * first name, last name,
  * address (street, zip code, city, country),
  * telephone.

We require this data in order to verify who the dealer’s contractual partner is, to form the basis of and provide the content of purchase agreements, to assist in the processing of purchase agreements and to get in contact with you when necessary. The data shall also be sent to the dealer for this purpose in the event of a purchase request being made or a purchase agreement being concluded with this dealer.

**e.** **Information on the Chrono24 and Private Seller services by e-mail**

**We are constantly striving to improve and develop our Platform.  
To be able to inform you about Chrono24, our services and news that may interest you as a user, Private Seller or dealer, we will from time to time send you e-mails to the e-mail addresses stored for you. You may withdraw consent to use of your e-mail address at any time without incurring any costs other than the transmission costs in accordance with the base tariffs. Please address your objection to  if you do not wish to receive any information on the Chrono24 service. Withdrawal of or failure to provide consent shall not pose an obstacle to conclusion of a contract or use of our Platform or services. **

**f.** **Newsletter**

You shall receive our newsletter so that we can provide you with information by e-mail. The newsletter will be sent to you only if you have expressly and separately agreed to this.

You may unsubscribe from the newsletter any time by sending us an e-mail to  or using the link at the bottom of the newsletter. 

**g.** **When using a contact form**

You can use a contact form to get in contact with us or with dealers/Private Sellers via the Platform. To do so, you must provide the following information:

  * name,
  * e-mail address,
  * telephone,
  * message.

These data are saved by us, and if you are sending a message to a Private Seller or dealer, they will be forwarded to that party.

**h.** **When leaving a comment in our magazine**

In our magazine at [http://www.chrono24.com/magazine/](http://www.chrono24.com/magazine) you can leave a comment on the articles posted there. The following fields are mandatory: 

  * name,
  * e-mail address,
  * comment.

We use these voluntary details to be able to publish your comment and to give other users the opportunity to respond to it. We need your e-mail address in order to be able to get in contact with you and follow up on any legal violations.

**2.** **Forwarding of data to third parties for contractual purposes**

We shall forward your personal data to third parties only if you have expressly agreed to this, if we are under a legal obligation to do so, or if this is required in order to assert our rights, in particular to enforce claims arising from the contractual relationship.

**3.** **Visibility of your data to third parties**

**a)** **Users and Private Sellers**

The personal data saved in your user account (myChrono24) cannot be viewed by third parties if you have not published any offers on the Platform. If you publish offers on the Platform as a Private Seller, registered and unregistered users can view your seller data on the Platform only if you have expressly agreed to disclosure of such. 

**b)** **Dealers**

If you are registered as a dealer and publish offers on the Platform, registered and unregistered users can view your seller data on the Platform as per item 1b) cc). During registration, and later within your profile, you can limit the visibility of your data to keep your address from being displayed.

**4.** **Registration with cooperation partner (Auctionata) of Chrono24**

Jointly with ISA Auctionata Auktionen AG, Kurfürstendamm 212, 10719 Berlin, Germany (hereinafter referred to as **"Auctionata"** ), Chrono24 offers "Chrono24 Live Auctions" for watches on an auction platform, accessible under the URL [http://auctionata.com](http://auctionata.com/) and <http://chrono24.auctionata.com/>. To take part in a live auction, you must be registered on the Auctionata platform. You can register with our cooperation partner Auctionata using the data from your Chrono24 user account. If you send a registration request to Auctionata, Chrono24 will transfer the following user data for the purpose of completing your registration form for Auctionata. However, this can only be done if you are also logged in to your user account on Chrono24 at the same time: 

  * company
  * first name, last name,
  * address (street, zip code, city, country),
  * telephone,
  * fax,
  * e-mail address.

Your data shall be deleted immediately by Auctionata if you do not confirm your registration or delete or alter an entry in the registration form.

Please also observe the data privacy policy of Auctionata: <http://auctionata.com/datenschutz>. 

Otherwise, no exchange or comparison of your data will take place between Chrono24 and Auctionata.

**5.** **Right to information, deletion and rectification**

You may request information at any time on the personal data stored by us under your name and/or view and alter said data by logging into our Platform using your login data. A formal request for information must be submitted in writing, along with proof of identity.

You can also delete or rectify your data and/or user profile at any time. You can do this by sending an e-mail to this effect to  or via the contact form. In the event that you delete your data, we hereby point out that you will not be able to use our services, or at least not to their full extent. 

**6.** **Data security**

We use appropriate technical and organizational security measures to protect the personal data stored by us under your name against manipulation, partial or total loss, and unauthorized access by third parties. Our security measures are being continually improved in line with technological developments.

If you register as a user with us, access to your user account is only possible once you have entered your personal password. You should always treat your access information as confidential and close the browser window when you finish communicating with us, particularly if you share the computer with other users.

We also take internal data privacy very seriously. Our employees and the service providers commissioned by us are obligated to maintain secrecy and comply with data privacy provisions.

**7.** **Cookies**

Cookies help in many different ways to make your visit to our Platform easier, more comfortable and more intuitive. Cookies are alpha-numerical information files that your web browser automatically stores on the hard drive of your computer when you visit our internet site. Cookies do not harm your computer’s hard drive.

We use cookies in order to be able to identify you as a registered user without your having to log in separately, for example. The use of the cookies does not allow us to receive new personal data about you as an online visitor. The majority of internet browsers accept cookies automatically. However, you can configure your browser to reject cookies or to notify you whenever you receive a new cookie.

Third-party service providers, including Google, also use stored cookies in order to place adverts on websites on the basis of your previous visits to this website. You may revoke your consent to the collection and storage of data at any time with effect for the future.

As an alternative to changing the settings on your browser, you can also opt out from the use of cookies for interest-based advertising by Google at [www.google.de/settings/ads](http://www.google.de/settings/ads). More information on this is available at [www.google.de/privacy/ads](http://www.google.de/privacy/ads). You can also find additional information on Google terms and conditions at [www.google.com/intl/de/privacy](http://www.google.com/intl/de/privacy). 

Alternatively, you can opt out from the use of cookies by third-party service providers by accessing the opt-out page of the Network Advertising Initiative at [www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp). 

Please note that opting out does not mean that your browser will remain deactivated even after the opt-out cookie has been deleted.

Deactivation of cookies can lead to your not being able to use all of the functions of our Platform. More information on deactivating cookies can be found at: [http://www.meine-cookies.org](http://www.meine-cookies.org/). 

**8.** **Links**

This data privacy policy does not cover websites that are linked to from our website. We do not have any influence over whether our data privacy and security standards are upheld by these sites. The operators of linked sites are solely responsible for the content thereof.

**9.** **Web analysis services**

**a.** **General information**

To shape our website according to needs and to continually optimize our service, we use web analysis services (“Google Universal Analytics” by Google Inc. and “MobileAppTracking by Tune”). Within this context, pseudonymized usage profiles are created and small text files that are saved on your computer (“cookies”) are used. The information collected by the cookie on your use of this website such as

  * browser type/version,
  * operating system used,
  * referrer URL (the page visited previously),
  * host name of the accessing computer (IP address),
  * time of server access,

is transmitted to a server in the US and stored there. The information is used to evaluate use of the website, to compile reports on website activity and to provide further services associated with website and Internet use for the purposes of market research and needs-based design of these web pages. This information may also be forwarded to third parties as appropriate, insofar as this is prescribed by law or insofar as these parties process the data on behalf of the commissioning party. On no account will your IP address be linked with other data of the service providers. IP addresses are anonymized to exclude all possibility of such association (IP masking).

The user can prevent the installation of cookies by adjusting his/her browser accordingly; however, we must point out that in this case not all functions of the web site may be available to the user to their full extent.

Alternatively, the providers of the web analysis services offer various options to prevent the information generated by the cookie from being collected and further processed. You can find more information on the various options in Section 9.d).

**b.** **Hotjar**

We also use Hotjar, a web analysis service by Hotjar Ltd., Level 2, St Julians Business Centre, 3, Elia Zammit Street, St. Julians STJ 1000, Malta. In this context, cookies are placed. The cookies are automatically deleted after 365 days. You can find an overview of the cookies used [here](http://docs.hotjar.com/docs/cookies-stored-by-hotjar). 

The information recorded by the cookies is transferred to servers in the Europe and stored there. The information is used to record anonymously the behavior of visitors to our website. Mouse movements and clicks, for example, are recorded. This does not apply to recording key strokes when entering passwords or payment data. The evaluation of the information is used to provide a more user-friendly website design. 

Recording and evaluating the information does not allow us to identify you personally. The information is anonymized through the use of the so-called UUID (Universally Unique Identifier). This allows us to identify repeat visitors to our website without being able to personally identify the person. 

Your data is not passed on to third parties except where there is a statutory obligation to pass on the details or if the data is processed for us by a third party (e.g. in a computer center). 

If you do not want Hotjar to record your behavior on our website, in addition to changing the corresponding cookie settings in your browser, you can disable JavaScript in your browser. 

More detailed information on data privacy when using Hotjar can also be found in the [Hotjar Privacy Policy](https://www.hotjar.com/privacy). 

**c.** **“Google Universal Analytics”**

Apart from cookie-based web analysis, we also use the analysis tool “Google Universal Analytics”, within the scope of which we allocate a unique user ID to every user upon registration or initial log-in. This user ID together with the behavior of the user on our platform – with, however, no reference to any of the user’s personal data – is forwarded to the Google servers. Google subsequently evaluates this user behavior on our behalf and compiles reports on user activity in order to provide further services associated with website and Internet use for the purposes of market research and needs-based design of our web pages. If IP addresses are collected during this evaluation, these shall be anonymized in such a way that the identity of the user cannot be determined.

We personally create no user profiles from the reports received by Google Inc. that would enable specific users and their personal data to be identified.

**d.** **“Google Analytics Advertising Features”**

We use Google Analytics Advertising Features to support display advertising. Apart from the Google Analytics cookie, another double-click cookie is set for this purpose. In addition to the anonymized data on user activity, demographics and interests data are also collected with the double-click cookie. Google evaluates this data on our behalf and draws up remarketing lists on the basis of specific behavioral data, demographics and interests data. Google shares these lists with AdWords. Demographics and interests data are also used by Google on our behalf to prepare analytics report and segments.

We personally create no user profiles from the reports received by Google Inc. that would enable specific users and their personal data to be identified.

**e.** **Objection**

The user can object to the creation of usage profiles at any time.

To do so, please follow the instructions ofthe providers of the web analysis services used by us:

  * You may object to the use of Google Universal Analytics at <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=de>
  * You may object to the use of MobileAppTracking by Tune at <http://optoutmobile.com/optout/index.html>
  * You may object to the use of Hotjar by the installation and use of a browser add-on such as [Ghostery](https://www.ghostery.com/), for example.

We use the Crashlytics tool to analyze why our app crashes and to improve its stability. According to the provider, no personal data are collected or transferred. Only real-time crash reports stating the time of the crash and information on receiver and location are transmitted. Please observe the data privacy policy of the provider <http://try.crashlytics.com/terms/privacy-policy.pdf>. 

**10.** **Social media plugins**

**a.** **Facebook**

We use social plugins from Facebook on our website. To do this, we use the "Like" or "Share" button. This is a service provided by the US company Facebook Inc. (1601 S. California Ave, Palo Alto, CA 94304, USA).

If you visit a page on our website containing such a plugin, your browser will create a direct connection to the Facebook servers. The content of the plugin will be directly transferred to your browser by Facebook and integrated into the website by the browser.

When the plugin is integrated, Facebook will be informed that your browser has visited the corresponding page of our website, even if you do not have a Facebook account or are not logged into Facebook at the time. This information (including your IP address) is transferred directly to a Facebook server in the USA by your browser and stored there.

If you are logged into Facebook, Facebook can directly match your visit to our website with your Facebook account. When you interact with the plugins, for example by pressing the “Like” or “Share” button, the corresponding information is also transferred directly to a Facebook server and stored there. The information will also be published on Facebook and displayed to your Facebook friends.

Facebook can use this information for the purposes of advertising, market research and needs-based design of Facebook pages. Facebook creates usage, interest and relationship profiles, for example in order to evaluate your use of our website in terms of the advertisements integrated into your Facebook profile, to inform other Facebook users of your activity on our website, and to provide further services associated with your use of Facebook.

If you do not want Facebook to be able to match data collected via our website with your Facebook account, you must first log out of Facebook before visiting our website.

The purpose and scope of data collection and further processing and use of the data by Facebook, as well as the related rights and settings options for protecting your privacy, can be viewed in [[Facebook’s data privacy policy]](http://www.facebook.com/policy.php). 

**b.** **Twitter**

We have also integrated plugins from the messaging network Twitter Inc. (795 Folsom St., Suite 600, San Francisco, CA 94107, USA) into our web pages. The Twitter plugins (“tweet” button) can be recognized by the Twitter logo on our pages. An overview of the “tweet” button can be found [[here]](http://dev.twitter.com/). If you visit a page on our website containing such a plugin, a direct connection is created between your browser and the Twitter server. Twitter will be informed that you have visited our site from your IP address. If you click on the Twitter “tweet” button while logged into your Twitter account, you can link the content of our site to your Twitter profile. Twitter can therefore match your visit to our site with your user account. We would like to point out that we, as the provider of the site, have no knowledge of the content of the transferred data or its use by Twitter. More information on this can be found in [[Twitter’s data privacy policy]](http://twitter.com/privacy). 

If you do not want Twitter to be able to match your visit to our site with your account, please log out of your Twitter user account.

**c.** **Google+**

Our website uses the +1 button of the social network Google+, which is operated by Google Inc. (“Google”), Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. The button can be recognized by the “g+1” symbol on a white or colored background.

When you access one of our website pages that contains such a button, a direct connection is established between your browser and the Google servers. The content of the “+1” button is transmitted directly to your browser by Google and integrated by it into the website. We have, therefore, no influence on the scope of the data collected by Google with the button. According to Google, if you do not click on the button, no personal data are collected. Only the data, including the IP address, of those users who are logged in, are collected and processed.

Find more information on the purpose and extent of data collection as well as the further processing and use of data by Google, your rights with regard to the above and settings to protect your privacy in [[Google’s data privacy policy]](http://www.google.com/intl/de/policies/privacy/). 

If you are a Google+ user and do not want Google to collect data on your person via our website and link it with your Google membership details, you must log out of Google+ before visiting our website.

**11.** **Information, rectification, correction and deletion of data**

You have a right to information regarding the personal data stored under your name as well as a right to rectify incorrect data, or to block and delete data.

For information on your personal data, to have incorrect data corrected, to have data blocked or deleted, or for further questions on the use of your personal data, please contact:

Tel.: +49 721 480889-80

Fax: +49 721 480889-88

E-Mail: 

You can also view and alter your data at any time by logging into our website with your login data.

You can delete your data and/or entire user profile at any time. You can do this by using the corresponding option in your user profile or by sending an e-mail to this effect to datenschutz@chrono24.com.

We point out that if you delete your data, you will not be able to use our services, or at least not to their full extent, and that you will need to re-register.

**12.** **Validity of the data privacy policy**

This data privacy policy is currently valid and dates from September 24, 2015

It can be viewed and printed at any time on our website 

<http://www.chrono24.de/info/datenschutz.htm>

**Chrono24 GmbH**
